Work planning is figuring out how you're actually
going to conduct the analysis —
and it's thinking through not only
what those specific analyses are,
but the order in which you're going to do them,
and who's going to do them.
When you think about work planning, it is important
that you link the issue tree to the work plan.
One way to think about this is to take each of the
branches, or nodes, at the ends of your issue tree,
and think about, for each of those:
what's the hypothesis you have?
For that hypothesis, what's the rationale
for it to be true or not true?
And for that rationale —
what is the analysis you need to do to confirm it?
Ultimately, what is the source of that insight —
be it quantitative or qualitative data —
that is going to be the input into the analysis
to support the rationale,
which refutes or proves your hypotheses
and allows you to resolve these issues.
Once you've developed your hypotheses and the rationale,
and listed out the analyses and sources of insight,
you can then think about the timing of those,
and who's going to do them,
and what the interdependencies between those are.
The key thing is to think about the burden of proof
for the hypothesis you're testing.
There are different ways the problem-solving
process can go awry.
One is not being clear about what that burden of proof is.
When you think about the key decision-maker, I've seen many
cases where people spend a lot of time and energy doing analysis,
and they go and discuss it with the key decision-maker,
who says: “That's not good enough.”
Understanding what that burden of proof is —
knowing what the bar is — is incredibly important.
There are cases where, almost no matter how much data
you put in front of somebody, they won't change their mind.
Better you know that from day one,
not two months down the road.
Conversely, if the burden of proof is actually
lower than what you think it is,
and you don't know that, you can spend a lot of time and
energy getting to a more precise answer than you need.